RISM Collections at New York University Conferences Guide to the Records of New Perspectives on Caribbean Studies: Toward the 21st Century and Prospects for Caribbean Basin Integration (Conference held at Hunter College, CUNY, August 28-September 1, 1984) RISM RG 16 (j)
New York University Archives
- Series VIII. Photographs, August 28 - September 1, 1984 (at the Reed Foundation)
  - Subseries b. Digitized Copies of Prints
    - Session XII. Closing Session and Awards Ceremony
      - foreground: Mighty Sparrow; background: Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, unidentified individuals, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-139)
      - foreground: Mighty Sparrow; background: Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, unidentified individuals, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-140)
      - Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, Mighty Sparrow, unidentified individuals, Archie Singham, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-141)
      - June Anderson, Leslie Lett, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-142)
      - June Anderson, Leslie Lett, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-143)
      - Livia Moller, June Anderson, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-144)
      - Jane Gregory Rubin, Reed Rubin, Vera D. Rubin, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-145)
      - Mighty Sparrow, Joan Sanders, unidentified individual, George Lamming, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-146)
      - l. to r.: Norman P. Girvan, Maurice A. Odle, Jorge Heine, Lloyd Best, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-147)
      - l. to r.: Norman P. Girvan, Maurice A. Odle, Jorge Heine, Lloyd Best, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-148)
      - l. to r.: Wilfred Cartey, Irene Comitas, Reed Rubin, Christine Donovan, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-149)
      - Serving table, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-150)
      - Adolfo Aguilar, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-151)
      - Lord Nelson, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-152)
      - Lord Nelson, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-153)
      - Lord Nelson, different view, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-154)
      - Lord Nelson, different view, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-155)
      - RISM staff: Sheila Bourne, Judith Selakoff, Leanna Selakoff, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-156)
      - l. to r.: Dessima Williams, Peter Weiss, Cora Weiss, Lucille Mair, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-157)
      - l. to r.: Dessima Williams, Peter Weiss, Cora Weiss, Lucille Mair, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-158)
      - Israel D. Drori, Frank McGlynn, Robert L. Hess, Frances Hess, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-159)
      - Israel D. Drori, Frank McGlynn, Robert L. Hess, Frances Hess, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-160)
      - Joseph Murphy, Mighty Sparrow, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-161)
      - Joseph Murphy, Mighty Sparrow, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-162)
      - Howard Dodson, Sybil Lewis, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-163)
      - Lucille Mair, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-164)
      - Archie Singham, Mighty Sparrow, M. G. Smith, Irene Comitas, Lloyd Braithwaite, Ursula Braithwaite, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-165)
      - Archie Singham, Mighty Sparrow, M. G. Smith, Irene Comitas, Lloyd Braithwaite, Ursula Braithwaite, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-166)
      - M. G. Smith, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-167)
      - Merle Hodge, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-168)
      - Robert A. Manners, Archie Singham, Helen McEachrane, Alistair Hennesy, Sybil Lewis, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-169)
      - Robert A. Manners, Archie Singham, Helen McEachrane, Alistair Hennesy, Sybil Lewis, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-170)
      - l. to r.: Peter Weiss, Lloyd Braithwaite, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-171)
      - l. to r.: unidentified individual, Lloyd Braithwaite, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-172)
      - Rex Nettleford, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-173)
      - l. to r.: Adolfo Aguilar, Lambros Comitas, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-174)
      - Michael Manley, Peter Weiss, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-175)
      - l. to r.: George Lamming, Michael Manley, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-176)
      - l. to r.: Jorge Sol, Peter Weiss, Michael Manley, Sep 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-177)
  - Subseries c. Digitized Copies of Contact Sheets
    - Roll 43: 37 images (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-178)
    - Roll 47: 36 images (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-179)
    - Roll 49: 35 images (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-180)
  - Subseries d. Printed Photographs
    - Session XII. Closing Session and Awards Ceremony
      - l. to r.: Michael Manley, Vera D. Rubin, Jorge Sol, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-109)
      - l. to r: Michael Manley, Vera D. Rubin, Jorge Sol, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-110)
      - l. to r: Michael Manley, Vera D. Rubin, Jorge Sol, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-111)
      - l. to r: Michael Manley, Vera D. Rubin, Jorge Sol, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-112)
      - Elizabeth M. Thomas-Hope, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-113)
      - Jorge Sol, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-114)
      - Jorge Sol, Michael Manley, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-115)
      - Jorge Sol, Michael Manley, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-116)
      - l. to r: Demetrio Boersner, Lloyd Barnet, Jorge Heine, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-117)
      - Archie Singhman and daughter, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-118)
      - l. to r: Michael Manley, Peter Weiss, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-119)
      - l. to r: George L. Beckford, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-120)
      - l. to r: Unidentified individuals, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-121)
      - l. to r: Cora Weiss, Joseph Murphy, Archie Singham, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-122)
      - Beasley Haycock, unidentified individual, Dennis Benn, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-123)
      - Beasley Haycock, unidentified individual, Dennis Benn, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-124)
      - Beasley Haycock, unidentified individual, Dennis Benn, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-125)
      - l. to r: Erroll Hill, Peter Harvey, unidentified individuals, Lloyd Braithwaite, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-126)
      - l. to r: Unidentified individuals, Don Mills, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-127)
      - l. to r: Wilfred Cartey, unidentified individual, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-128)
      - l. to r: Peter D. Phillips, George L. Backford, Trevor M.A. Farrell, Hillary McEachrane, Sybil Lewis, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-129)
      - George Lamming, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-130)
      - George Lamming, Michael Manley, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-131)
      - l. to r: Helen McEachrane, Dennis Benn, Beasley Haycock, Robert A. Manners, Wilfred Cartey, Aisha Khan, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-132)
      - l. to r: Helen McEachrane, Dennis Benn, Beasley Haycock, Robert A. Manners, Wilfred Cartey, Aisha Khan, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-133)
      - l. to r: Helen McEachrane, Dennis Benn, Beasley Haycock, Robert A. Manners, Wilfred Cartey, Aisha Khan, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-134)
      - Helen McEachrane, unidentified individual, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-135)
      - Helen McEachrane, unidentified individual, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-136)
      - foreground: Mighty Sparrow; background: Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, unidenitified individuals, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-137)
      - foreground: Mighty Sparrow; background: Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, unidenitified individuals, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-138)
      - foreground: Mighty Sparrow; background: Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, unidenitified individuals, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-139)
      - foreground: Mighty Sparrow; background: Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, unidenitified individuals, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-140)
      - Robin Elliot, Vera D. Rubin, Mighty Sparrow, unidentified individuals, Archie Singham, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-141)
      - June Anderson, Leslie Lett, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-142)
      - June Anderson, Leslie Lett, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-143)
      - Livia Moller, June Anderson, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-144)
      - Jane Gregory Rubin, Reed Rubin, Vera D. Rubin, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-145)
      - Mighty Sparrow, Joan Sanders, unidentified individual, George Lamming, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-146)
      - l. to r.: Norman P. Girvan, Maurice A. Odle, Jorge Heine, Lloyd Best, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-147)
      - l. to r.: Norman P. Girvan, Maurice A. Odle, Jorge Heine, Lloyd Best, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-148)
      - l. to r: Wilfred Cartey, Irene Comitas, Reed Rubin, Christine Donovan, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-149)
      - Serving table, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-150)
      - Adolfo Aguilar, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-151)
      - Lord Nelson, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-152)
      - Lord Nelson, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-153)
      - Lord Nelson, different view, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-154)
      - Lord Nelson, different view, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-155)
      - RISM staff: Sheila Bourne, Judith Selakoff, Leanna Selakoff, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-156)
      - l. to r.: Dessima Williams, Peter Weiss, Cora Weiss, Lucille Mair, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-157)
      - l. to r.: Dessima Williams, Peter Weiss, Cora Weiss, Lucille Mair, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-158)
      - l. to r.: Israel D. Drori, Frank McGlynn, Robert L. Hess, Frances Hess, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-159)
      - l. to r.: Israel D. Drori, Frank McGlynn, Robert L. Hess, Frances Hess, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-160)
      - Joseph Murphy, Mighty Sparrow, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-161)
      - Joseph Murphy, Mighty Sparrow, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-162)
      - Howard Dodson, Sybil Lewis, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-163)
      - Lucille Mair, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-164)
      - Archie Singham, Mighty Sparrow, M.G. Smith, Irene Comitas, Lloyd Braithwaite, Ursula Braithwaite, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-165)
      - Archie Singham, Mighty Sparrow, M.G. Smith, Irene Comitas, Lloyd Braithwaite, Ursula Braithwaite, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-166)
      - M.G. Smith, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-167)
      - Merle Hodge, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-168)
      - Robert A. Manners, Archie Singham, Helen McEachrane, Alistair Hennesy, Sybil Lewis, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-169)
      - Robert A. Manners, Archie Singham, Helen McEachrane, Alistair Hennesy, Sybil Lewis, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-170)
      - l. to r.: Peter Weiss, Lloyd Braithwaite, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-171)
      - l. to r.: unidentified individual, Lloyd Braithwaite, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-172)
      - Rex Nettleford, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-173)
      - l. to r.: Adolfo Aguilar, Lambros Comitas, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-174)
      - Michael Manley, Peter Weiss, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-175)
      - l. to r.: George Lamming, Michael Manley, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-176)
      - l. to r.: Jorge Sol, Peter Weiss, Michael Manley, Sept 1, 1984 (Notebook 14A, Folder CC84-177)
- Series IX. Audio and Video Administrative Files
  Approximately .25 linear feet (4 folders). Arranged chronologically. This series includes a summary of tape highlights, partial video transcripts, correspondence relating to the recording process and curricula vitae of videographers.
  - Correspondence, curriculum vitae, notes, ephemera, July - Aug 1984; undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Videotape transcription sample, 36 min., undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Timeline for each videotaped session, undated (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, curriculum vitae, proposal, Jan - Mar 1985; undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
- Series X. Pre-Publication Papers, July 1984-December 1986, 1984-1986
  - Lists of conference participants, form letters, ephemera, May- Sept 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Requests for papers, Sept 1984-Feb 1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Abstracts A-G (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Abstracts H-Q, [1984] (Box 15, File 4)
  - Abstracts S-Z, list of abstracts, [1984] (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - List of abstracts, Mss. rec'd., Jun 1985; undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Post-conference form letters, Sept-Oct 1984 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Mailing lists, ephemera, Sept 1984 (Box 15, File 8)
  - Mailing lists [for labels], undated (Box 15, File 9)
  - Form letters by Vera Rubin and Lambors Comitas--conference publication, Dec 1984;June 1985 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--publishers, May-Jun 1984; Mar 1985; Oct 1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--permissions A-C, Oct 1984-Aug 1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence--permissions D-H, Sept 1984-Jan 1985 (Box 15, File 13)
  - Correspondence--I-R, Oct 1984-July 1985: undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence--permissions S-Z pamphlet, Oct 1984-Dec 1986; undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Series XI. Conference Manuscripts (unpublished) June 1984-January 1985
  2.0 linear feet (4 boxes). Arranged in order of presentation (see conference programs, Box 16, Folder 1). Although some Mss. titles differ from those listed in the conference programs, this series consists of original conference manuscripts. Highlights include the opening remarks by Vera D. Rubin (see Folder 3), original art work, the closing address by former prime minister Michael Manley and papers associated with the award ceremony. Based on the correspondence and tally sheets in this series, some Mss. were revised or formalized after the conference for publication. Several Mss. were not submitted.
  - Session I
    - Conference Programs, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - List of participant manuscripts, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Session I. Plantation Society and the Contemporary Caribbean
    - "Opening Remarks," Vera D. Rubin, [Aug-Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Plantation Economy and Banana Monarchy," Lloyd Best, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "Caribbean Sugar Plantations: Their Past, and their Probable Future," Manuel Moreno Fraginals, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "The Plantation Legacy and the Rise, Decline and Re-Emergence of Transitional Corporations in the Caribbean," Maurice A. Odle, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Overcoming Dependency," Jay R. Mandle, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "Reflections on Regional Agricultural Development: Constraints and Potentials," Patrick I. Gomes, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "Presence and Decline of the Counter-Plantation System in Dominca," Jean Casimir, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Discussion Remarks: "Comments on Plantation Society and the Contemporary Caribbean," Norman P. Girvan, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Session II. Stratification, Pluralism and Sociopolitical Dynamics
    - "Pluralism in the Non-Hispanic Caribbean," M.G. Smith, [June 1984] (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Pluralism in the Non-Hispanic Caribbean," M.G. Smith (rev.), [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Class, Race and Culture in the Caribbean," Ken Post, [Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Reforma y Revolutcion en el Caribe," Demetrio Boersner, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "Stratification and Social Class in the Hispanic Caribbean (with Special Emphasis on Puerto Rico)," Angel G. Quintero-Rivera, July 1984 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Francaso del Poder Oligarqico en Haiti y Alternativas de Cambio," Suzy Castor, Gerard Pierre-Charles, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "Francaso del Poder Oligarqico en Haiti y Alternativas de Cambio," (rev.) Suzy Castor, Gerard Pierre-Charles, Nov 1984 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - "Voodoo and Politics in Contemporary Haiti," (original and revised copies) Michael S. Laguerre, [Aug - Oct 1984] (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "Socialism y Nacionalismo en la Ideologia de La Izquierda del Caribe de Haba Inglesa," Andres Serbin [discussion remarks not included], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Session III. Theoretical and Applied Issues in Social Organization
    - "Anthropology of Caribbean Agrarian Formations," Frank McGlynn, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Power and Privilege in a Small Island Economy: The Case of Trinidad and Tobago," Carl D. Parris, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Social Class and Religious Experience: The Case of Jamaica," Diane J. Austin, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Caribbean Literature and the Schools," Merle Hodge [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Africans in the Diaspora: Changing Continuities In West Indian and West Africian Sex/Gender Systems," Constance Sutton, [Aug - Oct 1984] (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Ganja: "A Mono-Crop Alternative," Ansley Hamid [discussion remarks not included], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Session IV. Processes of Ethnicity, [Aug - Sept 1984]
    - "Dependenct and Loval Level Conflicts Agrarian Processes in Guyana and Coastal Ecuador," Marilyn Silverman (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Guaymi Labor on a United Brands Subsidiary in Bocas del Toro, Panama and Talamanca, Costa Rica," Philippe Bourgois, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "Ethnic Diversity on a Corporate Plantation," (rev.) Philippe Bourgois, Nov 1984 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Ethnicity, Consciousness, and Revolution: The Miskitu/Creole Question in Nicaragua," Galio Gurdian and Edmundo Gordon, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "The Tolupan (Jicaque) of Honduras: A Study of Culture Lost," Anne Chapman, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "The Decimation of the Indians in Guatemala," Adolfo Aguilar [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "Guyana at the Crossroads of Latin American Politics in the Caribbean." Rita Giacalone de Romero [2], Sept 1984 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "Guyana At The Crossroads of Latin American POlitics in the Caribbean." (rev.) Rita Giacalone de Romero [discussion remarks not included], Oct 1984 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Session V. Nationalism, Independence and Creative Florescence, [Aug - Sept 1984]
    - "Symbolic Expression of Polotics: Cricket and Carnival," Frank E. Manning, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "The Impact of National Consciousness on Arts and Literature," John Wickham, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Culture and Sovereignty," George Lamming, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - "Images of the Black Man in Caribbean Literature," Wilfred Cartey [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - "Cultural Identity and the Arts," Rex Nettleford, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - "Calypso and Social Confrontation in Trinidad: 1970 to Present," Gordon Rohlehr, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - "Overview: Nationalism, Independence and Creative Florescence," Errol Hill [discussion remarks not included], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Session VI. Political Economy and Sociocultural Change
    - "Migration and the Integration of Peoplse and Places," Roy Bryce-Laporte, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Ideological Responses: Black Power and Rastafarianism," Peter D. Phillips, Aug 1984 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Revolutionary Responses: The Case of Cuba," Nelson Valdes [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "The Development of Caribbean States in the Post-War Period," Carl Stone [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Perspectives from the Hispanic Caribbean," (aka) "La Crisis Economica del Caribe: De la Dependencia Tradicional a la Dependencia Financiera: El Caso de la Republica Dominicana," Jose Moreno, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Conceptos Sobre El Estado En Las Socioedades Del Caribe," Gerard Pierre Charles, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Transnational Banks and Backward Capitalism: The Caribbean in the International Division of Labor," Hibourne A. Watson, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Session VII. Public Health Indices Of Development
    - "Hypertension and Culture Change in the Caribbean," W.W. Dressler, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Medicinal Folk Uses of Ganja," (original and revised copies) Melanie Dreher, [Aug - Sept 1984]; Oct 1984 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Sociocultural and Ecological Factors Influencing Schistosomiasis in St. Lucia (W.I.)," (original and revised copies) Peter Dalton, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Health Services in Central America," (original and revised copies) Richard Garfield and Pedro Rodriguez, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "The Dilemma of Success: The Revolutionary Achievements in Nicaraguan Health," Thomas Bossert, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence; "Crisis of the Dominican Republic Medical Model. Alternatives for the Year 2000," Guarocuya Batista del Villar, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "Health Systems Development in the English-speaking Caribbean," Peter Carr, Jul 1984 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Discussion Remarks: "Public health Indicators of Development: A Commentary," L.O. Watkins, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Session VIII. Agriculture and New Technologies: Dependency and Self-Reliance
    - "Diversification as a Strategy for Agricultural Development in the Caribbean: The Case of Barbados," Israel D. Drori, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - "Technology Policy and Economic Transformation: The Fundamental Issues and an Agenda for Action," (original and revised copies) Trevor M.A. Farrell, [Aug - Sept 1984]; Mar 1985 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "Institutional Perspectives on Regional Agricultural Research and Training in the Caribbean: An Alternative Framework for the 21st Century," Lawrence A. Wilson, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "Toward Removal of Constraints to Agricultural Development: Some Perspectives on the Commonwealth Caribbean," E.B.A. St. Cyr and John A. Spence, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Science, Technology and Development in the Caribbean," (original and revised copies) Aaron Segal and Wal, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Fuel for Economy: Energy Investment to Reduce Oil Dependency," Verne W. Loose, Beata C. Lewis, Ronald Lohrding [note: see Originals-Correspondence Binder for original cover art], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Haitian Peasant Agroforestry and the Market for Wood: Microeconomic Prerequisites for Appropriate Technology," Gerald F. Murray [discussion remarks not included], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Session IX. Regional and International Migration: Development Issues and Policy Implications
    - "Issues of Core and Periphery: Labor Migrations and the New International Dividion of Labor," Saskia Sassen-Koob, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Population Perspectives of the Commonwealth Caribbean," Kacj Harewood, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "The Transnationalization of Caribbean Migration: Some Political Dynamica," Linda Basch, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Migration and Urbanization: The Case of Haiti," Michel S. Laguerre, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 7)